<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-12T18:44:56+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">ScrumWithMe.com</title><subtitle>An online resource for all things Agile</subtitle><author><name>Scott McLintock</name></author><entry><title type="html">Introduction to ScrumWithMe.com</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/10/test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to ScrumWithMe.com" /><published>2021-08-10T14:52:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-10T14:52:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/08/10/test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/08/10/test/">&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You have just taken the first step in learning how to work together to create effective and successful products. Together, we’re going to learn the ins and outs of the “agile” development process whilst reviewing the different frameworks with a focus on Scrum in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have worked in various roles within the digital sector covering all aspects of the product life cycle from digital design, front end devlopment, quality assurance and product ownership. I have also worked across various Agile and Waterfall based companies and it is for this reason I have gained an appreciation for Scrum and all that it has to offer. I am now starting a new journey in my career with the intention of becoming a certified Scrum Master working at &lt;a href=&quot;https://company.boxoffice.com&quot;&gt;The Boxoffice Company&lt;/a&gt; and invite you to join me as I share all that I learn and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-scrum-master&quot;&gt;What is a Scrum Master?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, the Scrum Master is accountable for establishing Scrum and it is their responsibility to help the other members of their team to understand Scrum as well as helping to constantly improve the practices and processes of day to day activities within the workplace. This can range from coaching team members to working alongside the Product Owner to effectively manage the Product Backlog as well as various other Scrum related responsibilities. Exactly what this means and how it is achieved will be described in detail throughout this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scrum Master certification is split into 3 levels that determine a person’s knowledge on the subject:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scrum.org/professional-scrum-master-i-certification&quot;&gt;PSM level I&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates a fundamental level of understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scrum.org/professional-scrum-master-ii-certification&quot;&gt;PSM level II&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates an advanced level of understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scrum.org/professional-scrum-master-iii-certification&quot;&gt;PSM level III&lt;/a&gt; demonstrates a distinguished level of understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Scott McLintock</name></author><category term="Scrum," /><category term="Introduction" /><summary type="html">Congratulations! You have just taken the first step in learning how to work together to create effective and successful products. Together, we’re going to learn the ins and outs of the “agile” development process whilst reviewing the different frameworks with a focus on Scrum in particular.</summary></entry></feed>